<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Brno Guide</string>
    <string name="cat_1">Architecture</string>
    <string name="cat_2">Natural Monuments</string>
    <string name="cat_3">Statues</string>
    <string name="cat_4">Theatres</string>
    <string name="a_4_title">Red Church</string>
    <string name="a_4_description">The Red Church (Czech: Červený kostel) is a Protestant Church in Brno, Czech Republic. It was designed by architect Heinrich von Ferstel and built up between 1863-1867. Nowadays it is used by the Evangelical Church of Czech Brethren. The building is a cultural monument.</string>
    <string name="a_2_title">Petrov</string>
    <string name="a_2_description">Cathedral of Saints Peter and Paul is located on the Petrov hill in the centre of the city of Brno in the Czech Republic. It is a national cultural monument and one of the most important pieces of architecture in South Moravia. The interior is mostly Baroque in style, while the impressive 84-metre-high towers were constructed to the Gothic Revival designs of the architect August Kirstein in 1904–5.</string>
    <string name="a_3_title">Parnas Fountain</string>
    <string name="a_1_title">Špilberk Castle</string>
    <string name="a_1_description">Špilberk Castle (German: Spielberg) is a castle on the hilltop in Brno, Southern Moravia. Its construction began as early as the first half of the 13th century by the Přemyslid kings and complete by King Ottokar II of Bohemia.</string>
    <string name="a_5_title">Villa Tugendhat</string>
    <string name="a_5_description">Villa Tugendhat is a historical building in the wealthy neighbourhood of Černá Pole in Brno, Czech Republic. It is one of the pioneering prototypes of modern architecture in Europe, and was designed by the German architect Ludwig Mies van der Rohe.</string>
    <string name="a_6_title">Brno Exhibition Centre</string>
    <string name="a_6_description">It was established in 1928. The centre occupies a site on 667,000 square metres (7,180,000 sq ft) and provides a total gross exhibition area of 203,523 square metres (2,190,700 sq ft) including open-air space and exhibition halls with an exhibition area of 72,057 square metres (775,620 sq ft). </string>
    <string name="n_1_title">Brno Reservoir</string>
    <string name="n_1_description">"The Brno Reservoir, previously known as the Kníničky Reservoir (Czech: Brněnská přehrada, also known as Prýgl in Hantec slang) is a dam on the Svratka River right outside the city of Brno, Czech Republic. The construction of a levee on the 56th river kilometre of the Svratka River, together with flooding of a valley with the Kníničky village in, created the Brno Reservoir. "</string>
    <string name="n_2_title">Babí lom</string>
    <string name="n_2_description">Lookout tower Babí lom is located in the southern flank of the same called top at an altitude of 562 m. Lookout tower provides a scenic view east towards Highlands of Drahanská vrchovina, west of the Žďárské vrchy, south-easterly direction, we can see the wooded hills of Chřiby and Ždánice Forest and if we look south direction, we will see part of Brno with the castle Špilberk.</string>
    <string name="n_3_title">Hády</string>
    <string name="n_3_description">"Hády Hill and the TV tower that sits atop it are a dominant sight from almost anywhere in the city. It is also a popular recreation zone. One part holds four former quarries: Jungle, Old Town Quarry, New Town Quarry, and Růžena Quarry. "</string>
    <string name="n_4_title">Kamenný vrch</string>
    <string name="n_4_description">You can find a great rarity in the Kamenný vrch settlement in Brno - there is a natural nature reserve named Kameňák. It is here that spring tens of thousands of large-flowered conchs flourish.</string>
    <string name="n_5_title">Špičák</string>
    <string name="n_5_description">It is the dominant above over the Adam\'s valley on the western ridge of the ridge Nad Střelci (527 m) in the Moravian Karst, in the north-west of the village Babice nad Svitavou, in the original place of the defunct wooden lookout pavilion.</string>
    <string name="n_6_title">Stranska skala</string>
    <string name="n_6_description">Stránská skála (often without diacritics as Stranska skala) is a hill and refers to a Mid-Pleistocene-Cromerian interglacial most important paleontological site in Central Europe. It is situated in the eastern part of Brno, Moravia near the city districts Židenice/Juliánov and Slatina, dating to approximately 600,000 BP, as supported by paleomagnetic dating.</string>
    <string name="s_1_title">Statue of Jobst Luxembourg</string>
    <string name="s_1_description">"Statue of Jost was made on the end for year 2015. In 1394 Jost joined a rebellion of Bohemian nobles against Wenceslaus, whom he had arrested at Prague Castle and later taken into custody by the Austrian. Peace was made but the king expelled Jost from Prague. Sigismund and Jost signed a mutual inheritance treaty in 1401, but later again fell out with each other. "</string>
    <string name="s_2_title">Mim</string>
    <string name="s_2_description">"The ‘Mime’ statue was created in 1986. It was originally supposed to be installed in front of Mahenovo divadlo (the Mahen Theatre), but local heritage authorities didn’t approve of this placement. The statue was finally installed in 2002 at Žerotínovo náměstí (Žerotín Square) in the place where a memorial to Klement Gottwald had been. That memorial was removed after 1989 when Bílý dům (the White House) ceased to be the residence of the City Committee of the Czechoslovak Communist Party. "</string>
    <string name="s_3_title">Brno astronomical clock</string>
    <string name="s_4_title">Red Army Soldier</string>
    <string name="s_4_description">"An equestrian statue was originally planned for this location at Moravské náměstí (Moravian Square). The foundation stone was unveiled in 1946, but the general design was changed in 1948. The figural statue, called ‘The Victory of the Red Army over Fascism’ was ceremoniously unveiled in 1955 to mark the 10th anniversary of the liberation of Brno. The statue of a Red Army soldier, almost five metres high, stands on top of a monumental pedestal. His left hand is raised above his head in a symbolic gesture, intended to convey ‘Don’t shoot; lay down your arms, the fight for Brno has ended.’ "</string>
    <string name="s_5_title">Justice</string>
    <string name="s_5_description">This sculpture depicting a man lifting a heavy block was installed on Moravské náměstí (Moravian Square) in 2010. Sculptor Marius Kotrba’s design was selected by an expert committee out of almost forty proposals. Like other sculptures in Brno, this one caused some controversy. One reason was that Kotrba abandoned the classic idea of justice as blind, and gave this symbol a new form.</string>
    <string name="s_6_title">Tribute to T. A. Edison</string>
    <string name="s_6_description">This square, featuring several large buildings and a sculpture, is also known as Maliňák. The Renaissance Revival style Mahenovo divadlo (the Mahen Theatre) was built in 1881 and 1882, based on a design by Ferdinand Fellner and Hermann Helmer. It was the first theatre in Europe completely fitted with electric bulbs, called ‘edisonky’ in Czech. This fact is commemorated by a three-metre wire sculpture, Pocta T. A. Edisonovi (Tribute to T. A. Edison), which looks like four intertwined bulbs.</string>
    <string name="t_1_title">HaDivadlo</string>
    <string name="t_1_description">"The HaDivadlo ensemble originally performed in Prostějov as Hanácké divadlo (the Haná Region Theatre). It moved to Brno in 1985. The ensemble moved several times within Brno; in 1991, when it merged with the ensemble of Ochotnický kroužek (the Amateur Circle), it moved to Sukova Street where Kabinet múz (the Cabinet of Muses) was established. "</string>
    <string name="t_2_description">Today, this experimental theatre with a glorious past is among the leading stages on the theatre map of not only Brno, but the entire Czech Republic. Its ensemble, which used to perform in such places as Dům umění města Brna (the Brno House of Arts), has performed at Dům pánů z Fanalu (the House of the Lords of Fanal) on Zelný trh (the Vegetable Market) since 1992.</string>
    <string name="t_3_title">Janáček Theatre</string>
    <string name="t_3_description">When this theatre opened in 1965, it was the biggest and best-equipped theatre in Czechoslovakia. It is currently undergoing extensive renovations, and so the opera and ballet ensembles have moved for at least a year to temporary alternative venues, performing mainly in Mahenovo divadlo (the Mahen Theatre). </string>
    <string name="t_4_title">Mahen Theatre</string>
    <string name="t_4_description">The Renaissance Revival style Mahenovo divadlo (the Mahen Theatre) was built in 1881 and 1882, based on a design by Ferdinand Fellner and Hermann Helmer. It was the first theatre in Europe completely fitted with electric bulbs, called ‘edisonky’ in Czech. This fact is commemorated by a three-metre wire sculpture, Pocta T. A. Edisonovi (Tribute to T. A. Edison), which looks like four intertwined bulbs.</string>
    <string name="t_5_title">Brno City Theatre </string>
    <string name="t_5_description">The Brno City Theatre’s ensemble is quite likely the busiest in Brno, as its members perform at least two productions every day. Its older and smaller stage, with an auditorium which seats 365, serves mainly for dramas; its larger hall, which seats 700, is used predominantly for musicals.</string>
    <string name="t_6_title">Reduta – National Theatre Brno</string>
    <string name="t_6_description">The theatre has undergone numerous renovations and modifications over the centuries. From 1945 to 1993, the opera ensemble of Státní divadlo Brno (the State Theatre Brno) performed here. It was reopened in 2005 following renovations that won the Grand Prix in architecture. </string>
    <string name="a_3_description">Parnas fountain (Czech: Kašna Parnas) is one of the most notable water fountains and barroque architectural monuments in Brno, Czech Republic. It is a dominant in the Zelný trh (Vegetable Market) square, located roughly in the middle of the square.</string>
    <string name="s_3_description">"Brno astronomical clock (Czech: Brněnský orloj) is a black stone monument in Brno, Czech Republic. It is situated at Náměstí Svobody, the main square in the Brno City Centre. The monument was proposed by Oldřich Rujbr and Petr Kameník. Every day at 11:00 it releases a glass marble, which the spectators can catch from one of four openings in the monument and they can take it with them as a souvenir. "</string>
    <string name="t_2_title">Goose on a String</string>
    <string name="a_1_pos">49.197689,16.603325</string>


</resources>
